Ladies and gentlemen, a very warm
welcome to ICICI Lombard General
Insurance Company Limited Q1 FI 20226
earnings conference call.
From the senior management, we have with
us today Mr. Sanjie Mantri, MD and CEO
of the company. Mr. Gopal Balachandran,
CFO,
Mr. Anand Singhi, Chief Retail and
Government Business. Mr. Mr. Girishesh
Nayak, Chief Technology and Health
Underwriting and Claims, Mrs. Sep
Gorada, Chief Corporate Solutions
International Bank assurance and Mr.
Gorov Aurora, Chief Reinsurance,
Underwriting and Claims for Property and
Casualty.
Please note that any statements commence
are made in today's call that may look
like forward-looking statements are
based on information presently available
to the management and do not constitute
an indication of any future performance
as future involves risks and
uncertainties which could cause results
to differ materially from the current
views being expressed.
As a reminder, all participant clients
will be in the listenonly mode and there
will be an opportunity for you to ask
questions after the presentation
concludes. Should you need assistance
during the call, please signal an
operator by pressing star then zero on
your touchstone phone.
I now hand the conference over to Mr.
Sanjie Mantri, MD and CEO ICIC Lombard
General Insurance Limited. Thank you and
over to you sir. Thank you so much. Uh
good evening to each one of you. Thank
you for joining the earnings conference
call of ICL Lombard General Insurance
Company for quarter 1 2026.
Let me give you a brief overview of the
trends we observed in the economy as
well as our industry followed by an
overview of the business. Post this our
CFO Mr. Gopal Balachand will share the
financial performance of the company for
the quarter ended June 30, 2025.
India's GDP growth for quarter 4
financial year 2025 surprised positively
at 7.4%.
And the fullear growth came in at 6.5%
according to according to the data
released by Mosby.
Key macroeconomic indicators such as GST
collections and performance of
infrastructure sector indicate some
positive momentum for quarter 1
financial year 2026.
RBI's cut in the repo rate by 50 basis
point in early June 2025. Income tax
incentives by government and benign
inflation is expected to augur well for
the domestic economy.
Let me now dwell on certain industry
trends which can have an impact on the
GI industry at large.
In the current quarter, the government's
continued emphasis on infrastructure
deployment by has fueled growth across
key sectors such as cement, steel,
infrastructure, and capital goods. With
the banking sector remaining healthy and
capital util and capacity utilization
exceeding historical norms, any increase
in domestic demand could serve as a
catalyst for private capital
expenditure.
These factors present a positive outlook
for the commercial of business in coming
quarters.
In quarter 1 2026 as per the data
published by CN and two wheeler segment
Drew by 1 and a half% and 7.2% Y
respectively.
However in quarter 1 financial year 2026
basis the data published by FA auto
industry has grown by 4.9%
the private car segment grew by 2.6%
registering 97 million in sales.
The two wheel segment has been seen a
modest growth of 5% contributed by
contributed by both urban and rural
consumers.
As the monsoon is forecasted to be
normal, we anticipate that it will
further fuel the rural demand.
Commercial vehicle has seen a growth of
7% which was led by strong growth in
electric three-wheeler category.
As an organization, we remain optimistic
for the motor business in coming months.
The health segment remains the largest
contributor to the industry, accounting
for 40.2% of the GDPI mix in quarter 1
2026.
Rising hiring activity, escalating
medical cost and sustained credit growth
are the key drivers fueling continued
demand for health insurance.
However, the overall industry growth
trajectory continues to be a to be
moderated by the impact of the 1 byN
accounting norm.
Despite this, the fundamentals of the
health insurance segment remain strong,
positioning it as a critical pillar of
long-term industry growth.
Given the favorable economic indicators
and positive regulatory environment, we
expect the general insurance industry to
continue the growth momentum in medium
to long term.
However, we remain vigilant on the
ongoing geopolitical developments which
may pose risk to both global growth and
Indian economy.
Let me now share on an update on key
industry level events.
Happy to share that recently launched
campaign Achakia Insurance LEA is an
commendable step by the general
insurance industry towards enhancing
awareness and consequently increasing
insurance penetration across diverse
customer segments.
This unified effort reflect the sector's
growing commitment to driving financial
protection and resilience in India. As
one of the leading players in this
industry, ICL Lombard is well placed to
contribute and benefit from the same.
Another key event wherein the country
was deeply affected was a tragic Air
India plane crash.
We extend a sincere condolences to the
families who lost their loved ones. An
event of this magnitude can have
profound effect on all those involved.
As an industry and as an insurer, we
responded swiftly prioritizing and
supporting the affected family members
and other stakeholders during this
difficult times.
Now coming to the industry performance
for quarter 1 financial year 2026,
the GDPI grew by 8.8% 8% for quarter 1
2026.
Excluding the impact of the 1 byN
accounting norm, the GDPI grew by 12.8%
for quarter 1 2026.
Excluding crop and marel, the GDPI grew
by 11.1% for quarter 1 2026.
Speaking on the specific segments within
the industry, the commercial segment
reported a growth of 13% for the period
ending quarter 1 financial year 2026.
The growth is majorly driven by improved
pricing and property lines of business.
The motor segment grew for the indust
growth for the industry stood at 8.7%
for the period quarter 1 2026. The
industry continues to witness
significant pricing pressure as
reflected by higher industry combined
ratio for the motor line of business.
The health segment including mass cell
grew by 8.1% for the period quarter 1
2026.
Within this, the group health line of
business grew by 9.6% for quarter 1
whereas the retail health growth stood
at 9.4% for quarter 1 2026 impacted by
the 1 byN accounting norm.
Speaking on the underwriting performance
of the industry overall the combined
ratio for the industry worsen to 112.6%
for financial year 2025 as against 112%
for financial year 2024.
The overall combined ratio for private
players worsened to 111.4
for financial year 2025 from 108.7% for
financial year 2024.
Industry combined worsening was largely
due to motor and of business. It stood
at 123.7%
for financial year 2025 with 118.5%
for financial year 2024.
As against this, our continued focus on
driving profitable growth has helped us
to show a combined ratio of 102.8 for
financial year 2025 versus 103.3% for
financial year 2024.
Also, it is pertinent to note that the
company's contribution to overall
underwriting losses is at 2.7%
only with a wiz and 8.7% market share
for financial year 2025.
I will now speak about a company's
performance across key business in
quarter 1 financial year 2026.
The company's GDP are registered a
growth of 6% as against the industry
growth of 8.8% 8% for quarter 1 2026.
Excluding crop and mass health, the
company's growth was at 3.4% compared to
the industry growth of 11.1%
for quarter 1 2026.
In the commercial line segment, our
growth stood at 6.8% for quarter 1 2026
as again the industry growth of 13% for
the same period.
The industry has seen an improvement in
pricing at an overall level. However,
there have been different levels of
price action within subcategories of
commercial lines. We continue to drive
profitability through prudent risk
selection and distribution growth. We
have maintained a leadership leadership
position in engineering and marine cargo
line of business.
In the motor segment, our growth stood
at 3.2% for quarter 1 2026 as against
the industry growth of 8.7%.
In the backdrop of elevated competitive
intensity, as stated earlier, we
continue to drive our strategy in motor
insurance based on granular portfolio
segmentation and distribution expansion.
We continue to maintain a leadership
position with a market share of 10.5%
for quarter 1 2026.
Our portfolio mix for private car,
two-wheeler, and commercial vehicles
stood at 54.8%,
27% and 18.2% 2% respectively in
comparison to the mix of quarter 1 2025
which stood at 51.5% 26% and 22.5%
respectively.
In health segment we grew by 1.9% for
quarter 1 2026 as against the industry
growth of 8.1%
as at quarter 1 2026 on a 1 byN basis.
Our retail health business line
continued to maintain the growth
momentum pursuant to which we have
gained the market share. We registered a
growth of 32.2%
as against industry growth of 9.4% as at
quarter 1 2026.
The continued innovation in retail
health products and investment in retail
health distribution has helped us to
increase market share which now stands
at 3.5% for quarter 1 2026 as against
2.9% for quarter 1 2025.
Our group health segment degree by 2.5%
for quarter 1 2026 when compared with
quarter 1 2025
resulting in a market share being at
10.1%.
This was essentially attributable
to lower growth in our group benefit
segment due to muted credit disbursement
coupled with impact of 1 by accounting
norms.
would now like to apprise you of other
key initiatives of our organization.
The initiatives under one team continue
to deliver measurable results
underscoring our commitment to
sustainable and profitable growth at the
organization level. A key initiative in
this journey has been the consolidation
of our customerf facing call center into
a unified one call center aimed at
standardizing practices, enhancing
operational efficiencies and delivering
a superior customer experience through
strategic technology interventions.
The integration of process under this
initiative resulted in a 78% increase in
productivity for quarter 1 2026 along
with deduction in headcounts of the
fresh acquisition team and service team
at 22% and 10% respectively.
Our digital service engagement has gone
up to 38% in quarter 1 2026 up from 22%
in quarter 1 2025.
This was made possible through use of
artificial intelligence, voice bot,
propensity modeling and targeted
campaigns.
We further improved our efficiency in
motor claims. Our preferred partner
network serviced 74.6% of our nonoem
claims in quarter 1 2026 up from 72% in
quarter 1 2025.
Launch launched in April of 2024, our
ISAK initiative has strengthened on
ground claim support for our health
customers.
In quarter 1 2026, the initiative
assisted over 28,000 customers,
reflecting an increase from 8,000
customers supported in quarter 1 of
2025.
This growth highlights a continued focus
on enhancing the customer experience and
delivering timely accessible support
during the critical moments.
Our digital platform continues to aid
our growth with visitors increasing 21%
year on year and increase in fresh
business by 69% yearonear. This is
fueled by a one-stop solution, I'll take
care app for all insurance and wellness
needs which surpassed 16.6 million
downloads.
Our focus on customer experience and
process efficiency has led to an NPS of
68 and 69 for health and motor claims
respectively for financial year 2025.
We have demonstrated resilience amidst
industry challenges. Maintaining a focus
on profitability
guided by our one is one team
philosophy. We continue to harness the
power of data technology and innovation
to drive our progress. Our robust
multi-product multi-istribution strategy
allow us to adopt strictly and serve our
customers more effectively while
delivering profitable growth.
I will now request Gopal to take you
through the financial numbers for the
recently concluded quarter. Thanks Anjie
uh and good evening to each one of you.
I will now give you a brief overview of
the financial performance of the
recently concluded quarter. We have
uploaded the results presentation on our
website and you can access it as we walk
you through the performance numbers.
With effect from October 1, 2024,
long-term products are accounted on a 1
byN basis as mandated by IDI. Hence, Q1
FI26 numbers are not comparable with
prior periods. Please refer to our
investor presentation for further
details. The gross direct premium income
of the company was rupes 77.35 billion
in Q1 FI26 as against rupees 76.88 8
billion in Q1 FI25 a growth of6%
as against the industry growth of 8.8%.
Excluding crop and mass sales GDPI
growth of the company was 3.4% viz with
the industry growth of 11.1% in Q1 FI26.
Our GDPI growth during the quarter was
primarily driven by growth in the
preferred segments. The overall GDP of
our property and casualty segment grew
by 6.8% 8% to rupees 26.77 billion in Q1
FI26 as against rupees 25.08 billion in
Q1 FI25. On the retail side of the
business, the GDPI of the motor segment
was at rupees 24.44 billion in Q1 FI26
as against rupees 23.69 billion in Q1
FI25 registering a growth of 3.2%.
The advanced premium numbers for the
motor segment was at 38.07 07 billion
rupees as at June 30, 2025 as against
37.17 billion as at March 31, 2025.
GDP of the health segment was at rupes
23.81 billion in this quarter as against
rupes 23.37 billion in Q1 last year
registering a growth of 1.9%. Our agents
which include the point of sale
distribution count was at 1 1 lakh
43,675
as at June 30 up from 1 lakh 40,736.
This was the number as at March 31 2025.
Our combined ratio stood at 102.9%
for Q1 FI26
as against 102.3%
for Q1 FI25. Our investment assets
during the quarter rose to rupes 554.53
billion as at June 30, 2025 up from
rupes 535.08 billion as at March 31,
2025. Our investment leverage net of
borrowings remained the same at 3.74
times as at June 30, 2025 and as at
March 31 2025.
Investment income was at rupees 12.88 88
billion in Q1 FI26
as against rupees 11.28 billion in Q1
FI25.
Our capital gains net of impairment on
investment assets stood at rupees 3.8
billion in Q1 FI26 compared to rupees
2.84 billion in Q1 FI25. Our profit
before tax grew by 28.4% to rupees 9.94
billion in Q1 FI26 as against rupees
7.74 billion in Q1 FI25.
Consequently, profit after tax grew by
28.7% to rupees 7.47 billion in Q1 FI26
as against rupees 5.8 billion in Q1
FI25. Return on average equity was at
20.5% in Q1 FI26 as against 19.1% in Q1
FI25. Solveny ratio was at 2.7 times as
at June 30, 2025 as against 2.69 times
as at March 31, 2025. This continues to
be higher than the minimum regulatory
requirement of 1.5 times.
As I conclude, I would like to reassure
that we remain committed and focused on
our strategy of innovation and driving
profitable growth, consistent and
sustainable value creation for all our
stakeholders while continually ensuring
that the interest of the industry and
our policy holders is in the forefront
at all times. Thank you and we'll be
open to take questions.
>> Thank you very much. We will now begin
the question and answer session. Anyone
who wishes to ask questions may press
star and one on the touchtone telephone.
If you wish to remove yourself from the
question queue, you may press star and
participants are requested to use
handsets while asking questions.
Ladies and gentlemen, we will wait for a
moment while the question queue
assembles.
To ask questions, please press star and
one.
First question is from Nishan Chawat
from Kota. Please go ahead.
>> Uh yeah hi uh thanks for uh taking my
question. Uh my my question is actually
on the commercial lines of uh you know
businesses uh you know somewhere at the
beginning you mentioned that uh pricing
has improved uh in this segment but uh I
think at the same time you also said
that you know there are different levels
of pricing and as I see you have you
know shrunk the market share a little
bit in this segment. uh so just curious
what is your view on this segment and uh
do you expect this to be uh you know a
profitability accretive uh in this
financial year.
>> Sure I think thanks Vishit for your
question. Uh the simple answer is I mean
uh overall yes with the overall
sentiments and pricing getting better we
do expect it to be more profitable. If
you remember uh last year when we were
you know reaching out in every possible
quarter we had spoken about the
excessive uh uh intensity and aggression
on the pricing front. Uh certainly
there's a bit of a semblance overall. uh
but uh we also said along with the
multiple sections and competitive
intensity that we have seen what we have
done is distributionled growth primarily
because on the larger corporate side or
the larger risk still there has been
some bit of a aggressive pricing which
has come in we've done what is required
uh to drive profitable growth for us uh
your your seek on do you expect it to
continue uh our firm belief is yes uh
and what market is doing at this point
is pricing risk appropriately
uh which was not happening otherwise in
the previous year.
>> So this should actually be kind of you
know profitability accretive this year
is what we are trying to say.
>> I mean the it's very difficult to
forecast the simple answer if pricing
improves it should be better than what
it is. Uh but you know fire as a
business plan has to play out over
quarters because it's driven by very low
frequency and very high severity.
uh but it should be profitive. It should
be profitable overall. My answer is yes.
Uh but it will have to play out because
it's driven by extreme losses as in when
it happens if it happens.
>> Uh yes, of course. Uh the other question
is uh you know on the loss ratio in the
health business uh if you could uh help
help us uh you know split it between the
uh you know retail and the uh group
business.
>> So nent uh uh I'm giving the group
numbers first which is corporate health.
Q1 last year was 97.9. This is the last
year Q1.
>> 97.9. That number for Q1 this year is at
95.7.
Uh on the retail indemnity again similar
periods. Q1 last year was 72.5.
Q1 this year is 74.3.
>> Uh got it. Thank you. Thank you very
much and all the best.
>> Thanks. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
The next question is from Madukar Lata
from the Wama Wealth Management. Please
go ahead.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Madukar
>> seem to have lost the line for Madukar.
We'll move to the next question. The
next question is from P Jane from Motila
Oswal. Please go ahead.
>> Yeah. Just uh just a follow up on the
loss ratio of the retail health. uh you
you mentioned it's gone up from 72.5
to 74.3.
Given that we would have had a very
strong growth on the fresh premium
uh would you say that the severity and
the frequency of uh retail indemnity has
gone up substantially.
So pra I think uh if you remember even
last year first quarter we did kind of
talk about a slight increase in
incidences. Uh so we do see that playing
out even for quarter one of this year.
So there has been definitely an increase
in uh incidents but u as you would have
seen when we even when we started the
last year quarter one number was 72.5
uh but by the time we ended if you would
have seen the number on a full year
basis of a retailers loss ratio ended at
about 67.9
>> uh so and and exactly to your point I
think what's helping us is uh the growth
that we are seeing uh largely kind of
aided by the ele elevate product
offering that we have been talking about
I think that continues to kind do well
and therefore this is just quarter one
and our expectation is pretty much in
line with the range of loss ratios that
we have spoken. I think in all fairness
the expectation is that we should kind
of uh end the end the year in that same
loss ratio range of 65 to 70%. That the
range that's the range at which we are
comfortable with and as of now I think
things seems to be pretty much looking
around uh within that range. uh this is
just a quarter one uh phenomenon
>> just uh and again the 32% growth that
you have seen on the retail retail
health uh how much would you add how
much of that would be say portability
and how much would it be from uh say you
know first-time customers to the
industry can you give some qualitative
comments there because uh that will help
us understand the quality of business
>> so pre in general I think if you look at
it I think our market share has been
very low right so I think uh as a
company we have had an aggregate market
share of 2.9 I think we have moved the
needle which is what we talked about to
move at about 3.5%.
And the endeavor for us is to obviously
kind of make sure that again if you
remember last quarter four we did speak
about the initiative that we're trying
to do on retaining our own customers. So
therefore in that sense obviously that's
a that's an area where we are actively
focusing on so that we are able to kind
of improve our own retentions and two
again the objective will be to try and
see if we can get more customers
particularly which are new to insurance.
uh to your point on what could be the
extent of portability we don't
separately call out that number but I
think clearly from our standpoint I
think what we can talk about is on a
relative basis I think the proportion of
what we would have seen as a rollover
whether it is quarter 1 or quarter 4 of
last year visibly what we have seen in
quarter 1 I think definitely that mix is
lower
>> okay and uh just coming back to the uh
motor segment uh what is your thoughts
on motor DP price do Do you think that
can come through?
>> So, hi P Sanjie.
We are also as much aware as you are.
There is enough and more news that we
can uh we are you know ourselves seeing
that something is expected. Has the
industry made the representation? Answer
is yes. Uh uh but we would not have any
update beyond that. Uh but it's it's
it's kind of expected. uh but uh in our
working and in our thought process and
in our sourcing the way we operate we
take things as they exist at this point
of time where there is no TP hike uh but
we we must share the optimism which is
there overall that since for last four
years almost there's been very little
that has happened on the TP side uh some
uh increase uh would be a relief for the
industry overall
Just to follow up on that can it happen
without a chairperson and the
regulators?
>> So uh the manner in which it gets
announced is more in consultation with
IIDA. So uh it can happen technically
but again this is something which is
beyond our embit and we don't want to
you know further uh dwell on this uh
structurally from whatever it's uh known
to us it's possible. I mean Gopal any
views on this?
>> No, I think only other thing that I
would add uh pre is I think uh
definitely what warrants a price
increase. I think this is what I think
the industry has been largely looking at
as in for example again similar to what
we have been speaking which is when we
see court compensation or court award
getting exhibited and the element of uh
uh claim inflation that you're required
to build as a part of the loss cost.
Definitely there is every reason for us
to believe that uh one should definitely
seek a price change. Exactly when will
it happen? How would how it would get
notified? I think honestly we'll have to
wait for it. But there is definitely a
case for the industry to seek a price
increase given the fact that for the
last few years uh we have not
necessarily seen in that sense a
meaningful price increase on third
party.
>> Thank you. The next question is from
Sankit Gora from Aventis Park. Please go
ahead.
>> Yeah. And thank you for the opportunity.
See the fire growth for for us has been
lower compared to industry and and we we
invariably are the market leaders after
probably new India in that business. So,
so just just wanted to understand that
given given the bulk of the business
happens in first quarter in in
commercial lines is it fair to say that
um maybe because of the pricing
environment um uh our expected growth
which was maybe meaningfully very higher
will remain at the current levels for
the full year.
>> Fair question. uh I if it is uh
something which you have to think in
terms of trend I believe bar growth can
also increase uh overall in coming
quarters but the bulk of the booking
booking does happen in first quarter to
that extent mathematically speaking uh
you are right uh however progressively
last year the discounting kept
increasing as quarters kept happening
right so the market kept hitting new
levels of discount so to that extent if
there is some bit of assemblance that is
coming in the industry should show
further positive trend as far as Yi
growth is concerned and in line with
that we would also like to believe and
back ourselves to say that we will also
see that positive trend continuing
however whether we will be able to
bridge the delta that is existing in
quarter one uh that our endeavor
obviously is uh to get that managed over
quarters and see that we stay where we
want to uh
it will be purely a function of uh how
the pricing elements are working out in
different sections and we will take a
call accordingly.
Got it. Got it. And and the second thing
which I wanted to understand is that if
I look at the motor growth based on the
mix what you disclosed in the PPT it
seems that you you degrrew largely in
the commercial vehicles while while your
growth in two two wheelers and cars
looks okay compared to overall growth.
So, so is it largely because of the um
intensive competitive environment or or
or or we recalibrating compared to what
we did last year um in that line of
business.
>> Uh no no San I think you're again spot
on. Uh see beginning of the year again
the normal inflation and all of that
comes through in our respective loss
ratios that is expected to uh happen. uh
and if there's no TP hike it does make
uh the overall maps adverse and and
logically speaking the cost of
acquisition to that extent should get
adjusted so that uh the TPI if it's not
there still the overall math falls in
place uh we did realize that the market
overall did not change the trajectory
and we felt to be a bit more prudent uh
at this point of time you you are spot
on Sankit yes that's what is reflective
of uh it is not that uh we don't want to
uh do the right thing and see CV also
showing positivity but uh it's purely a
function of selection which has made us
uh come out the way we have come out in
terms of outcome but we don't want to do
it and you know that the cost of
profitability
yes so the basically in simple words if
if if there is a price like say in
couple of months um then it trade to say
that you you might see a pullback or or
a better growth in in CV segment. So the
again the function is uh uh it's it's a
function of how the market reacts
further suppose I'm just giving a
scenario the simple answer to what you
said is logically yes it should work out
what you're saying but supposedly the
market reacts again much more sharply
and ends up throwing a lot more money
>> in terms of cost acquisition we will
again end up calibrating so uh logically
what you're saying should happen but
we'll have to wait till it plays out.
>> Got it. Got it. Perfect. And and last
one, crop insurance 1425 crores what we
did last year. Um uh today today we are
doing just 18 crores in the current
quarter. Maybe timing difference. So
given given you mentioned in the PP that
you won few clusters. So so is it fair
to say that there will be year-on-year
growth in the crop business in the
current year?
>> Uh yearon-year growth difficult to
envisize. See for crop most of the
things will come up for bidding next
financial year. This year there are very
few actions. So as luck could have it
the Maharashtra where we were already
there and this year should have lasted
has gone for retendering consequent to
which we had to rebuild. Uh whether
we'll be able to match it or grow only
time will tell but not too many
opportunities at this point of time uh
to see that we can exceed that number at
least at this juncture.
Yeah,
>> thank you.
>> All right.
>> The next question is from Nidesh Jane
from Invest. Please go ahead.
>> Uh, hi sir. Uh, thanks for the
opportunity. So my question is on
competitive intensity. So which are
these players who are uh who are
engaging in intense competitive
competition in at this point in time. uh
because uh last time these were mostly
private sector players but this time if
you look at the data industry data the
market share gain is happening from PSU
players.
>> So what is driving that and uh how do
you see that ending up? Uh last time
couple of players have so shown very
high losses and then competing intensity
reduces for one year but again we are
again seeing that competent intensity is
increasing. So how do you see this plays
plays out and what are the timelines
let's say when when this will taper off.
So desh I think the way I think we would
respond is uh I think all of this
thankfully is public information.
Therefore I think the market clearly
knows which companies are aggressive
which companies are kind of gaining
market share. So uh without specifically
kind of getting into names u I think
this is all there in the public domain.
I think all that I which is what we kind
of put out as a part of the uh opening
transcript as in to say that and which
is which is what we called out even last
year. I think on motors specifically if
you would have seen honestly there was
an expectation last year for the
industry to actually see an improvement
in combined uh which if you remember
kind of kind of finally ended the year
with a combined ratio of almost 124% for
the industry as a whole compared to
roughly about 118% that we had seen one
year back. uh so so that's that's how we
have kind of headed into the current
year and that's also the reason why if
you would have seen for us I think
relative to the industry growth in motor
which has been a single-digit number of
roughly about 8% plus uh our growth in
motor has been 3.2%. Uh so that's again
a conscious call. Now how long can some
of these players subsist uh elevated
competitive intensity? The good news is
again each for each of the companies
there is public disclosures on their
outcomes in terms of combined ratios. Uh
some of the companies have uh while
majority of the companies we have the
full year numbers some companies
possibly could have announced numbers
even for quarter 1 as we speak. Uh so
clearly it seems to suggest that the
market continues to stay uh competitive
at 124% plus honestly we don't
necessarily kind of see uh at an
aggregate level to be very uh in that
sense gaining market share but within
the segments obviously we will kind of
grow where we think it is appropriate
and you know just to add to it uh as an
entity we have to show tremendous uh
patience uh uh if you you know go Back
into the history last year in H1 we had
gained then we kind of moderated and
that kind of moderation continued but we
know that uh if there is uh this kind of
intensity which is at a very different
level at this point of time we are
willing to uh uh wait it out uh and we
know those cycles will come where we'll
have our opportunity.
>> Yeah the the only thing is that the time
difference between cycle is quite short.
We are just getting one year of uh time
period where the competitive intensity
is okay but again then some new set of
players keep coming in and competitive
intensity increases then so it's not
that the two three year period there is
upcycle in terms of uh reasonable
competitive intensity in the sector.
>> So fair point Nish but the fact of the
matter is if new players are coming they
also over long-term are expecting value
to be created and that's why they
attracting new players. Suppose there
are no new players coming also also
speaks out the fact that it's not doing
enough to attract capital. Uh I frankly
speaking my view to that is the other
way around and while that we would love
to have periods of you know uh 3 years 2
years as you mentioned uh but we are
very well equipped with a multi-lay
multi-roduct multi- channelannel uh
entity to manage these kinds of
variability. It's part of our day-to-day
existence. So at times from a investor
standpoint when you look at it you
wonder what's happening uh but as a
company you know and you see the numbers
from you know almost 2008 since the de
tariffing happened the industry grew at
15% and there about around that region
but we have probably grown at 13 and a
half almost a percentage and a half
lower over 2008 to 2025
uh but the CG profit growth of the
industry is 10 and probably 8 to 10% and
ours is almost 20%. So uh we we back
ourselves in these times also. We would
love to have it the way you are saying
uh and this keeps us agile also. So it
really doesn't worry us but from your
standpoint maybe you've got a point.
>> Sure. Uh thank you sir. That's it for
myself.
>> Thanks. Thanks.
>> Thank you.
Before we take the next question, a
reminder to participants that you may
press star and one to join the question
queue.
The next question is from Shria Shivani
from CLSA. Please go ahead.
>> Yeah, thank you for the opportunity. I
have two questions. First is on the uh
on the tragedy that you mentioned about.
I just wanted to understand has uh how
much of the claims have been uh uh
included in our uh performance this
quarter u with the hull losses have they
come in in this quarter or whether
they're going to come in the next
quarter and and I'm assuming there will
also be the personal accident bit uh so
that can be spread over some time I
understand but uh what has happened with
the aviation claim that I wanted to
understand uh second is on the long-term
policies. So, um I remember when this
was launched, there was a bit of
confusion or not confusion, the entire
way in which you are paying out
commissions to your distributor on the
long-term policy has also changed,
right? It'll be in that 1/3 format or
whatever whatever one by end format. Uh
so, has the behavior of the distributor
changed uh now that you're 69 months
into it? Uh in which product segments
has it changed? are some product
segments going to become one-year
product only instead of being long-term
because of this policy change have some
commentary around that those are my two
questions thank you
>> sure so uh so sh on the first one I
think again as as we have always said I
think it's very difficult to kind of
comment on uh individual claims I think
what we can say for sure is uh uh what
we have which is what we have been kind
of telling even earlier at the time when
the incident had happened uh given the
exposure that we have on the risk
the impact that we on that we have on
the net they have been completely kind
of provided for. So whatever results
that you see uh for quarter one factors
in for the likely uh impact of claims
because honestly we will not know when
the estimate will eventually play out
and but I think it is well within our
ability to kind of absorb such losses.
That's primarily the business that we
are in and therefore to that extent I
think we have been able to kind of
provide for uh estimates. This is uh
what we have as of 30th of June. Uh to
your second point on uh long-term
policies I think that's a flexibility
which I think clearly the market has uh
got. I think they have to decide in
terms of how do they want to incentivize
sourcing of policies. Uh as we speak
you're right we are into the third
quarter of the change. uh market still
continues to exhibit differentiated
behavior in terms of some of them
exhibiting uh some of them kind of
seeking a friend some of them obviously
willing to kind of take over a period of
time but if you ask us has there been
any major shift in the behavior relative
to what we had seen in Q3 and Q4 the
short answer is no we have not
necessarily seen any major shift
>> so so so there is no I I'll quickly
update you that uh as Gopal said the in
certain constructs of long-term uh there
can be differential practice Yes, but
more so on the health side, the industry
has been very unified in terms of
procuring uh long-term products. Uh
initially in initial quarters, we did
see the long-term sourcing getting
impacted for us because we had moved in
line with the regulation and others had
not moved. uh but uh uh thank god in
that sense that now the practice has
been uniformly addressed by each one of
them and from there on we all see uh
those numbers reverting back. So to that
extent here it is uh a positive sign and
uh the partners are also finding an
obvious benefit of doing long-term p
policies for the customers. Yes. So
there is uh normaly as far as health
part of the business is concerned on the
retail side.
>> Got it. Got it. And just on the first
question just a followup sorry uh how
much can we say is the uh is the total
combined ratio impact of that event
>> if there's a number
>> it is it's baked in and the fact that we
are not calling out otherwise we would
have called out that is something
>> usual share
>> and these are all estimates it is 55 but
uh it's uh addressed at this juncture
and we don't think it's appropriate to
call out that members.
>> Sure. Sure. It's okay. Um, thank you so
much. This was very useful. Thank you.
>> Thanks. Thanks.
>> Thank you.
Next question is from Madukar from Noama
Wealth Management. Please go ahead.
>> Hi. Uh, thank you for taking my
question. Uh, I I got disconnected in
between. So maybe you know this a little
bit of a repeat. Uh so when you point
out comparative intensity
uh are we seeing some letdown in
comparative intensity due to
uh increased uh due to uh probably
slightly lower commission payouts and
and because EUM uh ratios remain high
for a lot of private uh guys. Uh and is
it is it uh is it is it because of that
that the PSU uh guys are increasing
their share or is it that the PSU guy
PSU players pricing itself is uh lower.
Uh so so so that was uh one question I
mean you know why uh and what is your
expectation given that you know now uh
considerable amount of time has passed
and uh levels still remain very high for
uh a lot of the guys. So um so what is
your expectation uh on on what can
happen out there? Thanks.
>> Yeah. So Madukar I think uh you are
absolutely right. I think what will be a
key key watch will be because this will
be the third year of the glide path that
the regulator had uh uh announced in
2024. Um even if you look at public
disclosure of all the companies which is
now out for FI25 as we speak. Uh it's
been about 50% of those companies are
still yet to tow the line within the
limit of 30 or 35% that the regulator
has stipulated. So hence that will be
something that's that will be closely
watched for. Uh clearly if you recolct
even last year when the regulator had
kind of looked at these companies they
have been asked to kind of give a clear
road map every quarter uh in terms of
what is their plan to achieve the
numbers uh within that limit of 30 or
35. So hence that will be clearly a key
determinant for most of the players who
have not necessarily yet met the limits.
uh what could happen in terms of the
competitive intensities again which is
what we responded in response to one of
the earlier calls which is to say that I
think players who have chosen to be very
aggressive in the last 2 three years I
think you can clearly see basis there
public disclosures their combined ratios
have got significantly impacted and they
are kind of clearly calibrating growth
numbers uh and hence of course this is
market so obviously there are other set
of players who choose to then get a
aggressive in entirety when you put all
of this together which is why we called
out industry combined ratio still
continues to remain elevated at 113 and
within that motor continues to stay
elevated at 124. Okay. How long can this
subsist? Honestly,
honestly we believe that you cannot
continue to lose 25 cents to a dollar uh
for a very long period of time.
And also Maduker we also believe that
sometimes the solution you are seeking
on the EOM can be worse than the problem
and that's what Gopal is talking about.
You may want to chase uh business which
comes on a lower cost of acquisition at
a pricing which is very aggressive. Now
uh clearly if that's the solution
industry seeks uh to manage the um glide
path uh we will uh uh let them take that
call. Uh and to be fair, it's each one
to his own self on that. Uh but we'll
have to see how it plays out.
>> Right. Also uh a followup uh see even on
health because of the long-term policies
uh
how has industry sort of reacted in
terms of you know payment of uh
commission over there on the long-term
policies? That's uh one part of the
question. are most people
uh you know uh paying
>> the answer to that is it's all one by
hand we pay it on a yearly basis for
long-term health policy yeah
>> okay and on on renewal uh uh premiums uh
are we are we seeing some sort of
reduction in commission in in uh in
renewal
uh because that was one of the
expectations also given
>> it is and you are spot on the definitely
there's a delta which exists between the
fresh sourcing of health and the renewal
and to be fair it's at the industry
level it's not only for IC lumbar
>> right um Got it got it thank you thanks
>> thank you thank you
>> thank you before we take the next
question a reminder to participants that
you may press star and one to ask
questions
the next question is from the go from
city please go ahead. Hi sir uh just two
questions. One on the group health part
obviously u you had kind of moderated
your growth u trajectory somewhere
towards the second half of last year
given the competitive pressure. So I
just wanted to get some sense you know
with your base kind of normalizing from
let's say the second half of this year I
mean how do you see the growth in that
part of the segment and the competitive
intensity your loss ratios have also
kind of improved a little bit on a y
basis. So how do you see that segment
behaving on the uh corporate employer
employee side and second on the retail
health portion of the business? I mean
um you know I think this question was
asked previously also but you know some
bad calculation would suggest that loss
ratios on the backbook are probably kind
of operating at levels which is which
may be a little bit higher than where
the industry averages are or maybe your
stated averages of around 65 to 70%
steady state run rate uh on the back
book I'm just talking about. So uh first
of all is the assumption correct and
secondly I mean if yes then how do you
kind of aim to recalibrate it?
>> So group health dependent I think uh I
think the call is pretty much similar to
what we spoke about on the rest of the
lines as well. Now this is a segment
where even Sanji had spoken about let's
say typically you get get to exhibit
maybe slightly chunky premium but maybe
comes at a very relatively lower cost of
acquisition. So hence uh competitive
intensity continues to be higher on that
particular segment given the fact what I
spoke about on possibly some companies
wanting to ride this segment of business
to meet their uh expensive management
obligation within that is how we have
played out our growth. So we will watch
for the development in case uh I think
if you see signs of easing for let's say
for companies who have to meet their um
then obviously I think we are well
placed uh to write the risk back. The
good news as we keep saying in our cont
in our business is majority of our risks
are one-year risks and therefore to that
extent our ability to possibly get it
back uh is always there with us and on
the second one I think
>> on the second one on the retail uh
health uh which was more with respect to
sorry loss issue
>> the law the loss is which you're talking
I think Gopal has already spoken about
it uh we do believe that coming quarters
so this is uh you know the mix the way
it comes out and the lot of NEP that
comes in and we have seen a bit of a
frequency spike here and there. Uh but
your backend calculations spot on and we
do believe that uh as a company we would
fare a lot better in coming quarters as
the growth of new would start uh you
know uh overall impacting our loss
ratios positively. So your calculation
is right and we are also expecting a
similar trend.
Uh got it. Uh thank you sir and all of
us.
>> Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> The next question is from Mirage who's
an individual investor.
>> Call on hold. Please stay on.
>> Yeah. Mira's lines seem to be on hold.
Uh that was the last question in quue.
I would now like to hand the conference
over to Mr. Sanjiv Mantri for any
closing comments.
>> Yeah. Right. Uh thank you. Thank you so
much for joining me. I think you all had
a long day back toback calls. They were
uh LDC live then you s potential now
it's Lombard. So enough and more calls.
Uh
look I mean we've spoken overarchingly
what we want to focus on and uh we look
forward to interacting with each one of
you in the course of the quarter. All
the best and take care of yourself.
Thank you so much.
Thank you very much
on behalf of ICI Lombard General
Insurance Company Limited. That
concludes the conference. Thank you for
joining us. Ladies and gentlemen, you
may now disconnect your lines.